

Email: sunyu@caltech.edu
Homepage: sunyumark.github.io
Google Scholar: scholar.google.com/sun.yu

I will be joining the Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering at Johns Hopkins University this fall. I am looking for Ph.D. and Master students. Feel free to fill this quick form to reach out.

BIOGRAPHY

I am a post-doctoral researcher in the Department of Computing and Mathematical Sciences at California Institute of Technology (Caltech) working with **Prof. Katie Bouman**. My research focuses on developing explainable and reliable AI algorithms for scientific imaging and computer vision. Prior to Caltech, I received my Ph.D. degree from Washington University in St. Louis (Wash U) supervised by **Prof. Ulugbek S. Kamilov**. My dissertation was the winner of the **2022 Turner Ph.D. Dissertation Award**.

Research Interests: Computational Imaging, Machine Learning, Computer Vision.

EDUCATION

Turner Ph.D. Dissertation Award

Department of Computer Science Washington University in St. Louis

Top in the class

Washington University in St. Louis, St. Louis, MO Ph.D. in Computer Science Advisor: Prof. Ulugbek Kamilov	Jan. 2018 – May. 2022
Washington University in St. Louis, St. Louis, MO M.S. in Data Analytics & Statistics	Aug. 2015 – May. 2017
Sichuan University, Chengdu, China B.S. in Electronic and Information Engineering Advisor: <i>Prof. Qinggong Guo</i>	Sep. 2011 – Jun. 2015
WORKING EXPERIENCE	
California Institute of Technology, Pasadena, CA Postdoctoral Fellow, Computing and Mathematical Sciences Department Advisor: <i>Prof. Katie Bouman</i>	Jul. 2022 – Present
Cedars Sinai Hospital, Los Angles, CA Clinical Data Research Specialist Mentor: Dr. David Ouyang	Aug. 2022 – July 2023
Nvidia, Santa Clara, CA Research Intern (Learning and Perception Research) Mentor: Dr. Orazio Gallo	May 2021 – Aug. 2021
Capacity, St. Louis, MO Developer Intern	May 2017 – Aug. 2017
AWARDS	

2022

Student Travel Award 2019

NeurIPS

Honor (top 15%) 2019-2021

Department of Computer Science Washington University in St. Louis

PUBLICATIONS

Pre-print: ('*' indicates equal contribution)

[p 2.] Z. Wu, Y. Sun, Y. Chen, B. Zhang, Y. Yue, and K. L. Bouman "Principled Probabilistic Imaging using Diffusion Models as Plug-and-Play Priors." **Preprint**.

[p 1.] **Y. Sun**, Z. Wu, Y. Chen, B. T. Feng, and K. L. Bouman "Provable Probabilistic Imaging using Score-Based Generative Priors." **Preprint** arXiv:2310.10835.

Journal: ('*' indicates equal contribution)

- [j 15.] Z. Wu, T. Yin, **Y. Sun**, R. Frost, A. V. D. Kouwe, A. V. Dalca, and K. L. Bouman "Learning Task-Specific Strategies for Accelerated MRI." **IEEE Trans. Comput. Imag.**, in press.
- [j 14.] P. Goyes-Peñafiel, E. Vargas, C. V. Correa, Y. Sun, U. S. Kamilov, B. Wohlberg, and H. Arguello, "Coordinate-Based Seismic Interpolation in Irregular Land Survey: A Deep Internal Learning Approach," IEEE Trans. Geo. Rem. Sen., vol. 61, pp. 1-12, 2023.
- [j 13.] R. Liu*, **Y. Sun***, J. Zhu, L. Tian, and U. S. Kamilov, "Recovery of Continuous 3D Refractive Index Maps from Discrete Intensity-Only Measurements using Neural Fields." **Nature Machine Intelligence**, vol. 4, pp. 781–791, 2022. [Impact Factor = 27.2]
- [j 12.] W. Gan, Y. Sun, C. Eldeniz, J. Liu, H. An, and U. S. Kamilov, "Deformation-Compensated Learning for Image Reconstruction without Ground Truth," IEEE Trans. Med. Imag., vol. 41, no. 9, pp. 2371-2384, 2022.
- [j 11.] **Y. Sun**, J. Liu, M. Xie, B. Wohlberg, and U. S. Kamilov, "CoIL: Coordinate-based Internal Learning for Tomographic Imaging." **IEEE Trans. Comput. Imag**, vol. 7, pp. 1400-1412, 2021
- [j 10.] J. Liu, Y. Sun, W. Gan, X. Xu, B. Wohlberg, and U. S. Kamilov, "SGD-Net: Efficient Model-Based Deep Learning with Theoretical Guarantees." IEEE Trans. Comput. Imag., vol. 7, pp. 598-610, June 2021
- [j 9.] **Y. Sun***, Z. Wu*, X. Xu*, B. Wohlberg, and U. S. Kamilov, "Scalable Plug-and-Play ADMM with Convergence Guarantees." **IEEE Trans. Comput. Imag.**, vol. 7, pp. 849-863, July 2021.
- [j 8.] M. Torop, S. Kothapalli, **Y. Sun**, J. Liu, S. Kahali, D. A. Yablonskiy, and U. S. Kamilov, "Deep learning using a biophysical model for Robust and Accelerated Reconstruction (RoAR) of quantitative and artifact-free R2* images." **Magn. Reson. Med.**, vol. 84, pp. 2932-2942, 2020.
- [j 7.] X. Xu, **Y. Sun**, J. Liu, B. Wohlberg, and U. S. Kamilov, "Provable Convergence of Plug-and-Play Priors with MMSE denoisers." **IEEE Signal Process. Lett.**, vol. 27, pp. 1280-1284, 2020.
- [j 6.] G. Song, **Y. Sun**, J. Liu, and U. S. Kamilov, "A New Recurrent Plug-and-Play Prior Based on the Multiple Self-Similarity Network." **IEEE Signal Process. Lett.**, vol. 27, pp. 451-455, 2020.
- [j 5.] J. Liu, Y. Sun, C. Eldeniz, W. Gan, H. An, and U. S. Kamilov, "RARE: Image Reconstruction using Deep Priors Learned without Ground Truth." IEEE J. Sel. Topics Signal Process., vol. 14, no. 6, pp. 1088-1099, 2020.
- [j 4.] Z. Wu, Y. Sun, A. Matlock, J. Liu, L. Tian, and U. S. Kamilov, "SIMBA: Scalable Inversion in Optical Tomography using Deep Denoising Priors." IEEE J. Sel. Topics Signal Process., vol. 14, no. 6, pp. 1163-1175, 2020.

- [j 3.] **Y. Sun***, J. Liu*, and U. S. Kamilov, "Block Coordinate Regularization by Denoising," **IEEE Trans. Comput. Imag.**, vol. 6, pp. 908-921, 2020.
- [j 2.] **Y. Sun**, B. Wohlberg, and U. S. Kamilov, "An Online Plug-and-Play Algorithm for Regularized Image Reconstruction." **IEEE Trans. Comput. Imag.**, vol.5, no.3, pp.395-408, September 2019.
- [j 1.] **Y. Sun**, Z. Xia, and U. S. Kamilov, "Efficient and accurate inversion of multiple scattering with deep learning," **Optics Express**, vol.26, no.11, pp.14678-14688, May 2018.

Conference: ('*' indicates equal contribution)

- [c 13.] W. Shangguan*, Y. Sun*, W. Gan, and U. S. Kamilov, "Learning Cross-Video Neural Representations for High-Quality Frame Interpolation." European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), Tel Aviv, Israel, October 23-27, pp. 511-528. [Acceptance rate: 1492/5803 = 26%]
- [c 12.] M. Xie*, J. Liu*, **Y. Sun**, B. Wohlberg, U. S. Kamilov "Joint Reconstruction and Calibration using Regularization by Denoising." Proc. IEEE Int. Conf. Comp. Vis. Workshops (**ICCVW 2021**), 2021
- [c 11.] J. Liu, Y. Sun, W. Gan, X. Xu, B. Wohlberg, and U. S. Kamilov, "Stochastic Deep Unfolding for Imaging Inverse Problems," Proc. IEEE Int. Conf. Acoustics, Speech and Signal Process (ICASSP 2021), Toronto, Canada, June 6-11, pp. 1395-1399.
- [c 10.] **Y. Sun**, J. Liu, Y. Sun, B. Wohlberg, and U. S. Kamilov, "Async-RED: A Provably Convergent Asynchronous Block Parallel Stochastic Method using Deep Denoising Priors." International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR 2021). [Spotlight: 114/2997 = 4%]
- [c 9.] W. Gan, Y. Sun, C. Eldeniz, H. An and U. S. Kamilov, "Deep Image Reconstruction using Unregistered Measurements without Groundtruth." Proc. Int. Symp. Biomedical Imaging 2021 (ISBI 2021), Nice, France, April 13-16, pp. 1531-1534.
- [c 8.] X. Xu, J. Liu, Y. Sun, B. Wohlberg, and U. S. Kamilov, "Boosting the Performance of Plug-and-Play Priors via Denoiser Scaling," Proc. 54th Asilomar Conf. Signals, Systems, & Computers (ACSSC 2020), Pacific Grove, CA, November 1–5, pp. 1305-1312.
- [c 7.] Z. Wu, Y. Sun, J. Liu, and U. S. Kamilov, "Online Regularization by Denoising with Application to Phase Retrival," Workshop on Learning for Computational Imaging, ICCVW 2019, pp. 3887-3895.
- [c 6.] J. Liu, **Y. Sun**, X. Xu, and U. S. Kamilov, "Image Restoration using Total Variation Regularized Deep Image Prior," Proc. IEEE Int. Conf. Acoustics, Speech and Signal Process. (**ICASSP 2019**), pp.7715-7719.
- [c 5.] J. Liu, **Y. Sun**, and U. S. Kamilov, "Infusing Learned Priors into Model-Based Multispectral Imaging," IEEE International Workshop on Computational Advances in Multi-Sensor Adaptive Processing (**CAMSAP 2019**).
- [c 4.] **Y. Sun**, J. Liu, and U. S. Kamilov, "Block Coordinate Regularization by Denoising," Proc. Ann. Conf. Neural Information Processing Systems (**NeurIPS 2019**), pp. 382–392. [Acceptance rate: 1428/6743 = 21%]
- [c 3.] **Y. Sun**, B. Wohlberg, and U. S. Kamilov, "Plug-In Stochastic Gradient Method," Proc. International Biomedical and Astronomical Signal Processing Frontiers Workshop (**BASP 2019**), p.75.
- [c 2.] Y. Sun, S. Xu, Y. Li, L. Tian, B. Wohlberg, and U. S. Kamilov, "Regularized Fourier Ptychography using an Online Plug-and-Play Algorithm," Proc. IEEE Int. Conf. Acoustics, Speech and Signal Process. (ICASSP 2019), pp.7665-7669. [Oral]
- [c 1.] **Y. Sun** and U. S. Kamilov, "Stability of Scattering Decoder For Nonlinear Diffractive Imaging," Proc. 4th International Traveling Workshop on Interactions between Sparse models and Technology (**iTWIST 2018**), p.31. [Oral]

PRESENTATIONS & TALKS

[c 6.] ICCP 2023, Madison WI, USA, July 28-30.

Topic: 'Provable Probabilistic Imaging using Score-based Generative Priors'

[c 5.] ECCV 2022 (Virtual)

Topic: 'Learning Cross-Video Neural Representations for High-Quality Frame Interpolation'

[c 4.] ICIP 2021 (Virtual)

'SIMBA: Scalable Inversion in Optical Tomography using Deep Denoising Priors'

[c 3.] ICLR 2021 (Virtual)

Topic: 'Async-RED: A Provably Convergent Asynchronous Block Parallel Stochastic Method using Deep Denoising Priors'

[c 2.] NeurIPS 2019, Vancouver, Canada, Dec. 8-14.

'Block-coordinate Regularization by Desnoising.'

[c 1.] iTWIST 2018, Marseille, France, Nov. 21-23.

'Stability of Scattering Decoder for Nonlinear Diffractive Imaging.'

Invited Talks:

[t 10.] Johns Hopkins University EE department, Mar. 2024.

Topic: 'Turning Denoisers into Principled Imaging Solvers: Algorithm, Theory, and Application'

[t 9.] Georgia Tech CSE college, Mar. 2024.

Topic: 'Turning Denoisers into Principled Imaging Solvers: Algorithm, Theory, and Application'

[t 8.] EI Computational Imaging XXII, Jan. 2024.

Topic: 'Provable Probabilistic Imaging using Score-based Generative Priors'

[t 7.] EI Implicit Neural Representations for Inverse Imaging, Jan. 2024.

Topic: 'Implicit Neural Representation for Tomographic Imaging'

[t 6.] CVPR Computational Camera and Display Workshop, June 2022.

Topic: '3D Tomographic Microscopy using Neural Fields'

[t 5.] Rice University Imaging & vision seminar, July 2022.

Topic: 'Integrating physical and learning models for computational imaging'

[t 4.] Stanford Computational Imaging Lab, Jan 2022.

Topic: 'Integrating physical and learning models for computational imaging'

[t 3.] Boston University Computational Imaging Systems Lab, Dec 2021.

Topic: 'Integrating physical and learning models for computational imaging'

[t 2.] CMU Image Science Lab, Dec 2021.

Topic: 'Integrating physical and learning models for computational imaging'

[t 1.] Caltech Computational Cameras Group, Oct 2021.

Topic: 'Integrating physical and learning models for computational imaging'

PROFESSIONAL SERVICES

· Professional societies:

IEEE Signal Processing Society, Member

2022-present

- IEEE Signal Processing Society, Student Member

2018-2022

• Technical committees:

- IEEE Technical Committee of Computational Imaging (CI TC), Elected Member

2023-present

· Journal Editor:

· Journal Reviewer:

- Nature Communications (**Nat. Commun**)
- OSA Optica
- SIAM Journal on Imaging Sciences (SIIMS)
- IEEE Transaction on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (**TPAMI**)
- IEEE Journal of Selected Topics in Signal Processing (**JSTSP**)
- IEEE Transaction on Computational Imaging (TCI)
- IEEE Transaction on Signal Processing (TSP)
- IEEE Transaction on Image Processing (**TIP**)
- IEEE Signal Processing Letters (SPL)
- Signal Processing (SP)
- Applied Mathematics and Computation (AMC)
- Digital Signal Process (DSP)
- SPIE Journal on Electronic Imaging (**JEI**)

• Conference Reviewer/PC:

- International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR)	since 2021
- International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML)	since 2022
- Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS)	since 2020
- Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)	since 2022
- International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI)	since 2020
- IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing (ICASSP)	since 2020

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

As Course Teaching Assistant:

- CSE 585T Sparse Model for Imaging, Wash U. 2018 Fall.
- ESE 415 Optimization, Wash U. 2018 Spring, 2019 Spring, 2020 Spring.
- CSE 427S Cloud Computing and Big Data Application, Wash U. 2016 Fall, 2017 Spring, 2017 Fall.

SUPERVISED STUDENTS

Current Students (Co-advised with Prof. Bouman):

- Zihui Wu (Ph.D. student)
- Heriniaina Rajaoberison (Ph.D. student)

Past Students (Co-advised with Prof. Kamilov):

- Wentao Shangguan (M.S. CSE),
- Renhao Liu (B.S./M.S. CSE),
- Mingyang Xie (B.S. CSE, 2021),
- Yiran Sun (M.S., 2021),
- Weijie Gan (M.S. CSE, 2020, Co-supervised with Xiaojian Xu),
- Zihui Wu (B.S. CSE, 2020),
- Max Torop (M.S. CSE, 2020),
- Shiqi Xu (M.S. ESE, 2019),
- Jiaming Liu (M.S. ESE, 2018),

Now Ph.D student at Boston U.

Now at Google Inc.

Now Ph.D student at U. Maryland

Now Ph.D student at Rice U.

Now Ph.D. student at Wash U.

Now Ph.D. student at Caltech

Now Ph.D. student at Northeastern U.

Now Ph.D. student at Duke U.

Now Ph.D. student at Wash U.

- Zach Pewitt (M.S. ESE, 2018),
- Josehp Han (M.S. ESE, 2018),
- Jialong Zhang (M.S. ESE, 2018),
- Fangying Zhai (M.S. ESE, 2018)
- Chunyuan Li (M.S. CSE, 2018)

Now at Boeing Now at Deloitte Now at Schlumberger